What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
I'm not going to tell you that.
Yeah.
I am VP of Marketing at a software company.
Oh, I don't want to disclose my personal income.
So I'm an entrepreneur, and
we spend money, we make money.
We're going all around downtown Austin asking strangers the most
amount of money that they've ever made in a single year.
Stay tuned.
Give me, sir, a question for you.
My brother and my friend and I, we started a channel
at the University of Texas that we did a 1.4 million followers.
We were just asking people a few questions on the best piece of advice that they
could tell the younger generation of kids coming out of school, starting out in the real world.
So I even wanted to go
and do a quick interview with them.
Just ask a few questions on some of your advice.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
So I'm an entrepreneur, and
we spend money, we make money.
In what industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
Neurotechnology.
I'm in the business of getting people off psychiatric medication
and using frequencies and digital frequency patterns to restore mental health,
or what we call just general health.
So that life on life's terms
is a pleasure rather than a struggle.
If you were to go back to when you started your first
business, what is the number one thing that you would tell yourself?
Be careful financially.
Don't borrow money, and if you
do borrow money, be very, very careful.
The biggest mistake I ever made
was letting banks lend me money.
Always fund it yourself as best you can.
Friends and family, raise the money through
all the platforms that are available now.
But don't borrow the money from
the banks because you will regret it.
What has been your secret to
scaling your business throughout your career?
So I actually tell my team, because I actually am...
CEO of a public company,
and I run my own business.
And I tell everybody, you have your vertical managers, they
sit on top and they bark and they give orders.
And then you have your horizontal managers, where we
all sit at the table and we work together.
And only in a critical moment do I
basically pull rank and make a final decision.
So the most important part of running a business, scaling
a business, is surround yourself with a team of professionals,
or aspiring professionals, or like-minded individuals in the vision,
and come together and share that vision and listen.
We don't listen to people anymore.
We're ready for a fight.
We're ready to get in
the corner and go after it.
And we should never bring that into a business.
What company are you the CEO of right now?
Nexalan Technology.
We trade on NASDAQ.
We stimulate the brain with frequencies that have been shown through science and through FDA
approvals to normalize issues in the brain normally associated with mood disorders, mental health struggles.
Thank you so much for your time.
I really appreciate that.
Good for you guys.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, sir.
Question for you.
We started the channel that
we grew to 1.4 million followers.
Just asking people questions.
We're going to give people a few quick questions
on the advice they would tell the younger generation.
Actually, I'm just late meeting somebody.
Sorry about that.
Have a good night.
Okay, I'm going to the mall.
I'm going to go get this next one.
Come on.
So, I think something that's super funny about Hard Knocks
that not many people see is we go for interviews everywhere.
It doesn't matter if you're at the
ice cream shop at 9 o'clock at night.
You could be at the convenience store.
It's everywhere.
I mean, we're going to be
in line getting some ice cream.
We're getting some food.
And we got decked out in a suit, Rolex on.
You just hear James.
The famous words from James.
Excuse me, sir.
What's the best piece of
advice you tell your younger self?
You can't go anywhere without us.
You can't go anywhere.
We're always there, but we're always shooting our shot.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I am VP of marketing at a software company.
How can someone really break into
the tech industry in today's world?
Take on as many opportunities as you can.
So, when I started, I
started a lot of different startups.
I had opportunities with large companies.
I found a lot of my colleagues
were kind of pigeonholed into one specific role.
By staying in startups, I got
to touch a lot of different areas.
I did have a lot of
opportunities with a lot of different startups.
I did have a lot of one
to two year runs at smaller companies,
but I learned so much.
It let me grow faster than I think I would have if
I just took a really comfortable high paying job at the beginning.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Oh, I don't want to disclose my personal.
I mean, high six figures, really high six figures.
Yeah.
What do you think is more important?
What you know or who you know?
Who you know, 100%.
How have you been able
to connect, build those relationships?
First and foremost, you have to have really
healthy relationships in the role that you're in
because those ultimately will get
you additional roles later on.
And always just remember.
That you are a brand.
So if you're just out having a good
time, you don't know who you're going to meet.
And those could turn into really great opportunities.
And I hate to admit this, but I've ended
up with more business contacts than dates through online dating.
So I just you never know.
So we always ask people, is it
who you know or what you know?
What's your take on that?
Here's my best networking advice for anyone out there.
And this is someone that I preach.
I think who you know is very important, right?
You get your foot in the door.
You surround yourself with millionaires and billionaires,
people that are 10 steps ahead of you.
But once you're in those circles, you have
to find a way to provide value for them.
So that way you can stay in contact
with those people that you can stay establishing.
Continue those relationships.
If you don't bring anything to the table and you
don't have any skill sets or anything to offer that person.
You can't connect them with other people.
Then you're just a fucking waste man.
I think he knows it right on the head.
It's a perfect mix of both.
But if you can't provide value, why do
they want to connect you with other people?
And why do they want to connect with you?
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I've been in medical for 26 years.
I own my own business.
And what was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
I'm not going to tell you that.
My last question.
A lot?
Yeah.
Working for yourself.
It's not for everybody.
The biggest thing I would
tell any kid that's in college.
I've owned my own stem cell company for 17 years.
Got a kick-ass business doing over 4 million in revenue.
And I was the guy that always took chances.
If you're going to sit there and
wait and never take chances, good luck.
When you graduate, nobody cares,
honestly, after the first year.
The guy that immediately hires you, he
doesn't care where you go to school.
After that, it's you versus the rest of the world.
I tell people that I train and hire.
When you get out, I'm your competitor.
I've done this for 27 years.
And I will eat your freaking lunch away.
Final thing.
My old man died when I was 26 years old.
He said a couple things to
me, which I'll share them all.
The number one thing was he said, I don't
care if you sell paperclips or locomotives for a living.
People buy from people they like.
The other thing he said was,
son, don't sweat the small stuff.
Control the controllables.
Don't sweat all the other bullshit in life.
If you can't control it, don't worry about it.
You have to really cherish those moments.
What got cut was we ended up having like a 30-minute conversation with
this guy about some of his best life and career advice for us.
And just really all about that, like, you
got to be a hammer at all times.
It's like he said.
The cream rises to the top.
No fucking excuses.
Anyways, he's hiring.
So, anybody young and hungry, hit us up.
We'll give you his number.
Yeah, watch this guy's videos.
Does a great job.
Meets everybody.
Everybody you could ever possibly want to meet.
Keep hustling, bro.
Hey, the school of hard knocks.
You already know, man.
Let's go.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I was in the military for a few years.
Got out of the military.
Dove right into consulting and project management.
But the whole time, I
always had something on the side.
I always had some form of
entrepreneurial mindset, no matter what I do.
So, when I was in the military, I'd buy a
house, you know, at every duty station I was at.
And without even realizing, I
was becoming somewhat of an investor.
You know, I'd buy a house at one military base.
I had to change duty stations.
And I'd buy another house and I'd rent it out.
And I ended up doing
that until I acquired several houses.
And being that they were all on military
bases, there's always someone there to rent it out.
How many properties do you currently
have under your portfolio right now?
Right now, I have four.
But, you know, I flipped houses
in between and done things like that.
And I'm getting ready to offload all of them.
Right now, I'm kind of a cash poor, asset rich.
And I want to flip
that for the recession that's coming.
Right.
So that I can go all in on certain things that are really going
to 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10x in the next, you know, year or so.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Somewhere between $500,000 and $600,000.
Yeah.
That's incredible, man.
Thanks.
In your opinion, right, what is the
blueprint to becoming a millionaire in today's world?
So, in 60 seconds.
In 60 seconds, I can't really say.
But what I would say is create.
If you want to be a millionaire, create.
You can't just wake up and go with
the flow or do whatever you normally do.
You have to have a plan.
Live strategically.
Part of that is to be a millionaire.
And part of that strategic plan should be to create.
Create something.
Create a YouTube channel.
Create a product.
Find something that's broken and
find a solution to fix it.
Or recreate something that's already working well.
If you see someone doing something well, try to recreate it
and do it in your own format or your own way.
Add your own spin and your
own knowledge and twist to it.
Find something that's broken and fix it.
Find something that's working well and
replicate it and be strategic about both.
What was the importance of
taking risk at an early age?
Like, what kind of opportunities and
doors did that open up for you?
I went to Texas A&M for construction science
and I remember sitting in the classroom, you know,
looking at everyone in the class and knowing, like,
what was going to come after, like, the job.
I've already been on an internship and kind of
knew, like, what it would be like after that.
I was sitting there in the classroom and I
just thought to myself, like, I just got to jump.
My business that I had already started didn't
even hit any big strides yet or anything,
but I just thought to
myself, I can't work for someone.
I can't be, like, in this environment where I'm, like, told
what to do and just sit there and work for someone else.
And so I just kind of took the risk and
jumped and my junk removal company turned into a demolition company,
into a land clearing company and I'm
only 28 and started it at 21.
And I have two other businesses in addition to that.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
I would say about $650,000. Every month it's different.
Some months I'll make $75,000 and
the next month I make $10,000.
And you just, you never know. That's one of
the things too is like this all the time.
So you're 28 years old. What has been
your blueprint to becoming a millionaire in today's world?
Leverage real estate and maybe get, like,
a line of credit to even purchase it.
Or if you can get your
hands on, like, an asset like that,
I think that's probably one of the most
important things to do at an early age
because it'll just keep on appreciating over time
and it'll help you with your
credit as you're paying that off
and then maybe you can get renters or whatever.
And at least you have
an asset regardless of whatever happens.
If your business fails, whatever, you have something.
Even if you get your parents
to help you get your first house,
I think a piece of real estate is key.
Second, I would say have a plan and
think about, like, where you want to end up
and just work backwards from there.
If I want to build pools and
it takes all of these different mechanical,
electrical, plumbing, gunite,
shotcrete, concrete, this, that,
who does these things? Where are
they at? How good are they?
There's a lot of different pieces to the puzzle,
but just starting at the end and working
your way toward where you want to be.
And then, of course, the first
step is to build a plan.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
Well, lucky, I was in law enforcement.
I was with the Los Angeles
Police Department for about 30 years.
And what was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Well, I did celebrity weddings.
So I think at one point I was topping $300,000.
So what is your best financial
advice for the younger generation today
that you or someone told you
when you were coming out of school?
Invest.
My training officer, when I first came on, advised
me to not only just depend on the pension,
but invest in diversity.
I didn't have a say in it.
He told me, you're going to take it
and divert and have a pension in a divert,
we call it deferred comp program.
So you have two little buckets that
you can pull out when you get older.
So an LAPD, a police officer made
over $300,000 doing celebrity weddings and security.
Kind of crazy that you can actually
make that kind of money in law enforcement.
Question for you.
I wanted to know if we
could do a quick interview with you,
ask you a few questions on how you became successful
and your advice for the younger generation.
Sure.
Appreciate that. Thank you.
I appreciate that.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I have an electrical engineering degree,
but I work in cybersecurity and privacy right now.
And what has been the most amount of
money that you ever made in a single year?
Yeah.
What was the best financial decision
you ever made throughout your lifetime?
I don't know if I would call it financial decision,
but the best decision in my
lifetime was to major in engineering because,
you know, even though you have an engineering degree,
you can just do so many other things.
You don't have to be an engineer.
It just leads to a lot of
different areas that you normally wouldn't have
because it teaches you a lot about problem solving.
Absolutely.
Thank you so much for your time, sir.
I appreciate that.
I loved your answers.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
And stay tuned for tons of amazing content to come.
And click this video right here
to watch us going all around Houston
asking millionaires how they became successful.